export const BUSINESSMANAGEMENTA2017 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The ends that organizations strive to achieve are",
A: "ethics.",
B: "goals.",
C: "norms.",
D: "values",
answer: "B. goals.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. People responsible for directing the affairs of organizations are",
A: "employees.",
B: "employers,",
C: "managers",
D: "unions.",
answer: "C. managers.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following factors can lead to business failure?",
A: "Constant stocktaking",
B: "Evaluating performance",
C: "Greater flexibility",
D: "Uncontrolled expansion",
answer: "D. Uncontrolled expansion.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The management function which involves engaging people to carry out a task is .",
A: "planning.",
B: "organizing.",
C: "controlling.",
D: "directing.",
answer: "C. organizing.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The signing of cheques by a manager is part of his role are.",
A: "figurehead.",
B: "leader.",
C: "resource allocator.",
D: "spokesperson.",
answer: "C. resource allocator",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The ability to develop, organize and manage a business venture is",
A: "business planning.",
B: "entrepreneurship.",
C: "intrapreneurship.",
D: "joint venture.",
answer: "B. entrepreneurship.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. Which of the following marketing strategies should be adopted for a product in its growth stage?",
A: "Low prices are encouraged",
B: "New products should replace weak products",
C: "Promotional activities must be intensified",
D: "Promotional activities should be reduced",
answer: "C. Promotional activities must be intensified.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The procedures applied to check performance against set standards is",
A: "administration.",
B: "controlling",
C: "planning.",
D: "supervision",
answer: "B. controlling.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The act of assigning authority and responsibility in an organization is",
A: "Delegation.",
B: "decentralization.",
C: "span of control.",
D: "unity of command.",
answer: "A. Delegation.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A business that is locally owned and with very few employees working at a single location is",
A: "a small business.",
B: "a sole proprietorship.",
C: "a rural enterprise.",
D: "mail order business.",
answer: "A. a small business",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The integration of the various activities within an organization is",
A: "centralization.",
B: "decentralization.",
C: "co-ordination.",
D: "controlling.",
answer: "C. co-ordination.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. When a message is distorted along the channels of communication it depicts",
A: "communication gap.",
B: "filtering.",
C: "jargon.",
D: "miscommunication.",
answer: "A. communication gap.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The use of communication skills in bargaining to manage conflict and reach mutually satisfy outcomes is",
A: "arbitration.",
B: "conciliation.",
C: "negotiation.",
D: "resolution.",
answer: "C. negotiation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The desire for achievement and recognition are",
A: "affection needs.",
B: "esteem needs.",
C: "physiological needs.",
D: "safety needs.",
answer: "B. esteem needs",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The product concept involves",
A: "an idea of how a product should look like.",
B: "improving upon the quality of an existing or new product.",
C: "improving upon the production process.",
D: "various categories of product available for consumption.",
answer: "A. an idea of how a product should look like.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The right to control activities of other department as they relate to specific processes and policies is",
A: "chain of command.",
B: "functional authority.",
C: "line authority.",
D: "staff authority.",
answer: "B. functional authority.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Segmenting a market on the bases of age and gender is",
A: "benefit sought.",
B: "demographic.",
C: "geographic.",
D: "psychographic.",
answer: "B. demographic.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Initiating new projects to create change is part of a manager’s role as",
A: "a disturbance handler.",
B: "an entrepreneur.",
C: "a negotiator.",
D: "a shareholder",
answer: "A. a disturbance handler",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following activities uses the flow production process?",
A: "Carpentry",
B: "Refinery",
C: "Metal fabrication",
D: "Road construction",
answer: "B. Refinery.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. A type of decision which deals with unstructured problems is",
A: "non programmed decision.",
B: "operational decision;",
C: "programmed decision.",
D: "tactical decision.",
answer: "A. non-programmed decision.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. A period of supervised training required for qualifying for a profession is",
A: "internship.",
B: "off-the-job training.",
C: "on the-job-training.",
D: "vestibule training.",
answer: "C. on-the-job training",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. A tool for planning and controlling which measures relationship between two items is",
A: "break-even analysis.",
B: "budget.",
C: "financial ratio.",
D: "forecast.",
answer: "D. forecast.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Negotiation between management over condition of service and terms of employment is",
A: "collective bargaining.",
B: "conflict resolution.",
C: "consultative meeting.",
D: "work-to-rule.",
answer: "A. collective bargaining",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A document comprehensive information on the activities of a company throughout the preceding year is",
A: "account and report.",
B: "bank statement.",
C: "payroll.",
D: "performance appraisal.",
answer: "B. bank statement.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The specific work or task an individual is expected to perform in an organization is job",
A: "evaluation.",
B: "description.",
C: "design",
D: "specification.",
answer: "D. specification.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. When a computer keeps data until it is required at later date it is performing the function of",
A: "processing.",
B: "receiving.",
C: "retrieval.",
D: "storage",
answer: "D. storage.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The main objective of every organization is to",
A: "employ people.",
B: "make profit.",
C: "provide services.",
D: "sell goods.",
answer: "B. make profit.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. A consideration which consists of a promise to do something in the future is",
A: "executed consideration.",
B: "executory consideration.",
C: "future performance.",
D: "invitation to treat.",
answer: "B. executory consideration.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. A written statement of the education, experience and skills required to fill a vacancy in an organization is job. *",
A: "description.",
B: "design.",
C: "evaluation.",
D: "specification.",
answer: "A. description.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. An incomplete statement of a material fact is",
A: "misrepresentation.",
B: "mistake.",
C: "void agreement.",
D: "void contract.",
answer: "D. void contract",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A characteristic of common marker is",
A: "harmonization of economic policies.",
B: "restriction of the movement of capital and labour.",
C: "trade barriers.",
D: "varied external tariffs.",
answer: "A. harmonization of economic policies",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A market for trading in long term securities is",
A: "commercial bank.",
B: "development bank.",
C: "micro finance institution.",
D: "stock exchange.",
answer: "D. stock exchange",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. A refusal to honour one’s contractual",
A: "abrogation.",
B: "breach.",
C: "repudiation.",
D: "rescission.",
answer: "B. breach.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Recruitment, placement and training of employees in an organization are duties performed by the",
A: "human resource department.",
B: "legal department.",
C: "Production department.",
D: "public relation department.",
answer: "A. human resource department",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following features does not apply to a Bill of Exchange?",
A: "It must be an order",
B: "It must be signed by the drawer",
C: "It must be transferable",
D: "The order must be in writing",
answer: "C. It must be transferable",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. If a group of countries trade barriers between them and set same tariffs on goods coming from other countries, they are.",
A: "a common marker.",
B: "a customs union.",
C: "an economic union.",
D: "a free trade area.",
answer: "B. a customs union",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. One of the functions of a Central bank is",
A: "accepting deposits from the general public.",
B: "controlling money supply.",
C: "granting loans to individual.",
D: "operating as profit making organization",
answer: "B. controlling money supply",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. A written order instruction a bank to pay a specified amount over the counter is",
A: "Bill of Exchange.",
B: "Open cheque.",
C: "Promissory note.",
D: "Standing order.",
answer: "B. Open cheque.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. An order sent by an importer to his foreign agent for the supply of goods is",
A: "certificate of origin.",
B: "consular invoice.",
C: "freight note.",
D: "indent.",
answer: "B. consular invoice",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Effective communication in an organization can be enhanced by",
A: "talking with force.",
B: "the use of jargon.",
C: "using an interpreter",
D: "using simple language.",
answer: "D. using simple language.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A document issued by a seller to a buyer to inform him of any reduction in the amount owing is",
A: "credit note.",
B: "debit note.",
C: "delivery note.",
D: "invoice.",
answer: "A. credit note.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. A function of a Commercial Bank is",
A: "controlling money supply.",
B: "determining interest rate.",
C: "lender of last resort.",
D: "providing custody for valuables.",
answer: "D. providing custody for valuables",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following statements is not a factor to consider in promoting staff?",
A: "Ability to discharge higher responsibility",
B: "Education and qualification",
C: "Family ties and relationship",
D: "Quality of job performance",
answer: "C. Family ties and relationship.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. One of the challenges of developing countries in relation to international trade is",
A: "depreciation of currency.",
B: "export of processed goods.",
C: "increase.in the price of export.",
D: "large size of marker.",
answer: "A. depreciation of currency",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The pooling of risk is based on the principle of",
A: "contribution.",
B: "indemnity",
C: "large numbers.",
D: "proximate cause.",
answer: "A. contribution.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following documents gives tide to goods in international trade?",
A: "Bill of lading.",
B: "Certificate of origin.",
C: "Consular invoice.",
D: "Proforma invoice.",
answer: "A. Bill of lading",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Tax levied on goods imported is",
A: "customs duty.",
B: "excise duty.",
C: "income duty.",
D: "purchase tax.",
answer: "A. customs duty.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The form of foreign trade in which goods shipped to one port are subsequently re-exported is",
A: "barter trade.",
B: "counter trade.",
C: "entrepot.",
D: "manifest",
answer: "C. entrepot.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Mr. Kwame suffered a car accident. The insurance company compensated him and retained the scrap. This reflects the insurance principle of",
A: "insurable interest.",
B: "proximate cause.",
C: "subrogation.",
D: "utmost good faith.",
answer: "C. subrogation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. An example of government recurrent expenditure is",
A: "cost of road construction.",
B: "cost of building school.",
C: "payment of loans.",
D: "payment of salaries and wages",
answer: "D. payment of salaries and wages",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]